Mellonee V. Burnim Collection, 1861-1996, bulk 1976-1996 SC 7
Archives of African American Music and Culture
- 1. African American Gospel/Religious Music, 1976-1996; 104 Audiocassettes + 4 audiotape reels (3 hours, 54 minutes), 6 videotape reels; (approximately 98 hours)
  - 1.2. Interviews about Videotaped Gospel Performances, 1979-1980; 12 Audiocassettes 11 hours, 55 minutes
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with Keith Scott, Nathan Hall, Cheryl Keyes, and George Middleton, 1979 October 19; C302--C303; cass 1810--cass 1811; 2 Audiocassettes 147 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 379--CDREF 381
      See Burnim pages 250--304 for interview transcript
      Topics: Black denominations and worship styles, analysis of choirs and standards of dress, older gospel styles, Sarah Jordan Powell, white audience perceptions.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with James "Bubba" Crawford, Emma Neal, Patana Kendrick, 1979 October 31; C304; cass 1812; 1 Audiocassette 93 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 382--CDREF 383
      Topics: Definition of gospel music vs. other religious music.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with Joyce Jackson, Angela Hatchett, Iris Rosa, and Sarah Ritter, 1979 November 9; C305; cass 1813; 1 Audiocassette 93 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 384--CDREF 385
      Topics: Gospel sound, participants' movement and dress, communication between performers and audience.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with Betsy Peterson and Elaine Lawless, 1979 November 30; C306; cass 1814; 1 Audiocassette 71 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 386--CDREF 387
      Topics: Apostolic vs. Pentecostal churches, definition of gospel music vs. other religious music, Black vs. White congregations.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Interview with Betsy Peterson and Elaine Lawless, 1979 December 5; C309; cass 1817; 1 Audiocassette 57 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 390
      Topics: Apostolic churches, Mercy Mission congregation, ethnicity, gender, social identities, world views, church membership.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with 40 Members of Iris Rosa's A219 Black Dance Class, 1979 December 6; C307; cass 1815; 1 Audiocassette 26 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 388
      Topics: Movement and singing styles, shouting.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Group Interview with 40 Members of Iris Rosa's A219 Black Dance Class, 1979 December 14; C307--C308; cass 1815--cass 1816; 2 Audiocassettes 93 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 388--CDREF 389
      Topics: Speaking in tongues, Catholic vs. Baptist traditions.
    - Black Culture Center, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana. Feedback Interview with Paula Tadlock, 1980 February 2; C310; cass 1818; 1 Audiocassette 71 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 391--CDREF 392
      Topics: White vs. Black religious music styles, religious dance, rhythm in shouting style.
  - 1.3. Gospel Music Conventions, 1979-1995; 53 Audiocassettes approximately 43 hours
    - Pentecostal Assemblies of the World (PAW), New Orleans, Louisiana, 1979 August 18-19; 1 Audiocassette 86 minutes
      - Pentecostal Assemblies of the World (PAW), Hyatt Regency Hotel, New Orleans, Louisiana; Conversation with Stephanie Smith, Singer from Ypsilanti, Michigan, and Another Unidentified Woman at PAW, 1979 August 18-19; C21; cass 1801; 1 Audiocassette 86 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 368--CDREF 369
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America (GMWA), New Orleans, Louisiana, 1979 August 20-24; 5 Audiocassettes 4 hours, 13 minutes
      - "Chords, Bridges & Passing Progressions" Class by Dr. R. Simmons, 1979 August 20; C201; cass 1807; 1 Audiocassette 20 minutes
      - Concert Choirs from the East and South, 1979 August 20-21; C22; cass 1803; 1 Audiocassette 63 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 371
      - Interview with Curley King, Member of the Washington, DC Chapter, 1979 August 21; C202; cass 1808; 1 Audiocassette 46 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 376
      - Mass Choir Concert with James Cleveland, et al., 1979 August 24; C23; cass 1802; 1 Audiocassette 62 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 370
      - Mass Choir Concert with James Cleveland, Albertina Walker, Margaret Douroux, K. Pringle, C. Nix, and Others, 1979 August 24; C24; cass 1804; 1 Audiocassette 62 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 372
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America (GMWA), University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1992 August 13; 5 Audiocassettes 2 hours, 32 minutes
      - GMWA Concert with Take 6, Sarah Jordan Powers, Northern California Community Choir, 1992 August 13; 11-1; cass 1855; 1 Audiocassette 56 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 576
      - GMWA Convocation, Academic Division, 1992 August 13; 11-2; cass 1856; 1 Audiocassette 63 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 577
      - Interview with Ed Smith, Executive Director, GMWA, 1992 August 13; 11-3; cass 1857; 1 Audiocassette 43 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 578
      - Interview with Dr. Robert Simmons, Dean, GMWA Academic Division, 1992 August 13; 11-4; cass 1858; 1 Audiocassette 38 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 579
      - GMWA New Artists Concert with Carlton Fellows, approximately 1992 August 13; 11-5; cass 1859; 1 Audiocassette 12 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 580
    - National Convention of Gospel Choirs and Choruses (NCGCC), Chicago, Illinois, 1993 August 4-6; 3 Audiocassettes 2 hours, 38 minutes
      - Thomas Dorsey Convention, Alumni Chorale Concert, 1993 August 4; 12-1--12-2; cass 1860--cass 1861; 2 Audiocassettes 95 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 581--CDREF 583
      - Interview with Ralph Goodpasture, Minister of Music, First Church of Deliverance, Chicago, 1993 August 6; 13-1; cass 1862; 1 Audiocassette 63 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 584
        Audio quality is very poor and nearly unintelligible at points due to the equipment malfunctioning while making original recording.
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America (GMWA) 26th Annual Convention, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1993 August 6-15; 5 Audiocassettes 2 hours, 41 minutes
      - Interviews with Participants, 1993 August 13; 14-2; cass 1864; 1 Audiocassette 57 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 586
        Contents
        Evangelist Mesha Hobson, from Beloit, Wisconsin
        Patsy Jackson, music educator, from Ft. Worth, Texas
        Mary Jones, member of New Life Community Choir, Charlotte, North Carolina
      - New Artists Showcase with Kirk Franklin, 1993 August 13; 14-3; cass 1865; 1 Audiocassette 44 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 587
      - Interview with Rev. Kenneth Moales, NCGCC President, 1993 August 13; 14-4; cass 1866; 1 Audiocassette 44 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 588
      - Interview with Roger Holmes, Manager of the Richard Smallwood Singers, 1993 August 14; 14-1; cass 1863; 1 Audiocassette 13 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 585
      - Burnim's Recollections of GMWA 26th Annual Convention, 1993 August 15; 14-5; cass 1867; 1 Audiocassette 3 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 589
    - National Convention of Gospel Choirs and Choruses (NCGCC), Cincinnati, Ohio, 1994 August 8-11; 18 Audiocassettes 16 hours, 4 minutes
      - Greater Cincinnati Mass Choir, Pre-Musical, 1994 August 8; 17-1; cass 1869; 1 Audiocassette 94 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 590--CDREF 591
      - Children's Choir Rehearsal/Pre-Teens, 1994 August 8; 17-2; cass 1870; 1 Audiocassette 52 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 592
      - Young People's Choir Rehearsal/Youth Department, 1994 August 8; 17-3; cass 1871; 1 Audiocassette 22 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 593
      - Dr. Wyatt T. Walker, Tuesday Matinee Session, 1994 August 9; 17-4; cass 1872; 1 Audiocassette 93 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 594--CDREF 595
      - Tuesday Night Musical, 1994 August 9; 17-5; cass 1873; 1 Audiocassette 54 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 596
      - Soloists' Bureau Performance, with Tribute to Willie Mae Ford Smith, 1994 August 10; 17-6; cass 1874; 1 Audiocassette 94 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 597--CDREF 598
      - Wednesday Matinee Including Brief Interview about Conventions, 1994 August 10; 17-7; cass 1875; 1 Audiocassette 4 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 599
      - Interview with Joel Rolle, Bahamas Chapter Member and Choir Director in Bimini[?], Bahamas, 1994 August 10; 18-1; cass 1876; 1 Audiocassette 59 minutes
      - Interview with Ms. Gladys Berryman, NCGCC Historian, approximately 1994 August 9; 18-2; cass 1877; 1 Audiocassette 33 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 600
      - Wednesday Matinee, Southwest Region (Bahamas) and New Jersey Choral Union, approximately 1994 August 10; 18-3; cass 1878; 1 Audiocassette 40 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 601
      - Interview with Carol Antrom, Composer and Choir Director, 1994 August 11; 18-4; cass 1879; 1 Audiocassette 51 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 602
      - Interview with Johnny Lloyd, Supervisor to Willie Mae Ford Smith Soloists' Bureau, approximately 1994 August 9; 18-5--18-6; cass 1880--cass 1881; 2 Audiocassette 76 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 603--CDREF 604
      - Interview with Jackie Jackson and Willie J. Smith (Children of Willie Mae Ford Smith), 1994 August 11; 18-7; cass 1882; 1 Audiocassette 63 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 605
      - Mass Choir Rehearsal, 1994 August 11; 18-8; cass 1883; 1 Audiocassette 69 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 606
      - Rev. Kenneth Moales, Presidential Address and Performance, 1994 August 10; 18-9; cass 1884; 1 Audiocassette 61 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 607
      - Interview with Dr. Elon Wilks, NCGCC Board of Directors, 1994 August 11; 18-10--18-11; cass 1885--cass 1886; 2 Audiocassettes 79 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 608--CDREF 609
      - Interview with Robert Antrom, NCGCC Publisher, 1994 August 11; 18-12; cass 1887; 1 Audiocassette 20 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 610
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America (GMWA), Atlanta, Georgia, approximately 1994 August 16-18; 9 Audiocassettes approximately 7 hours
      - Thurston Frazier Memorial Chorale Rehearsal, 1994 August 16; 19-1; cass 1888; 1 Audiocassette 22 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 611
      - Mass Choir Rehearsal, 1994 August 16; 19-2; cass 1889; 1 Audiocassette 74 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 612--CDREF 613
      - Women's Choir Rehearsal with Paula Davis, Albertina Walker, and Shirley Johnson, 1994 August 16; 19-3; cass 1890; 1 Audiocassette 93 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 614--CDREF 615
      - Interview with Connecticut Chapter Member William H. Davis; Interview with Dorothy Sims, GMWA Historian and Member of Evangelistic Board, 1994 August 17; 19-4; cass 1891; 1 Audiocassette 51 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 616
      - Interview with Albertina Walker Brooks of Chicago, 1994 August; 19-5; cass 1892; 1 Audiocassette
      - Gospel Announcers Guild with Bobby Cartwright, Jr., 1994 August 18; 19-6; cass 1893; 1 Audiocassette 46 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 617
      - "Music as Ministry" Class with Margaret Douroux; Interview with Doris Rice about Douroux's Workshops, 1994 August 18; 19-7; cass 1894; 1 Audiocassette 24 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 618
      - Interview with Glen Burleigh, Composer, 1994 August; 19-8; cass 1895; 1 Audiocassette
      - Interview with Teresa Hairston, Managing Editor of Score Magazine, 1994 August; 19-9; cass 1896; cass 1897 (dup.); 1 Audiocassette 28 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 619
        cass 1896 is damaged. Access file and reference copy made from first generation copy cass 1897.
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America, Los Angeles, California, 1995 August 13-16; 7 Audiocassettes 6 hours, 22 minutes
      - Sunday Communion and Consecration Service, 1995 August 13; 21-1--21-2; cass 1900--cass 1901; 2 Audiocassettes 169 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 623--CDREF 626
      - Women's Chorus Rehearsal, 1995 August 14; 21-3--21-4; cass 1902--cass 1903; 2 Audiocassettes 97 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 627--CDREF 628
      - Interview with Terry K. Grimes, Supervisor of the GMWA Academic Division and Director of the Thurston Frazier Memorial Choir, 1995 August 16; 21-5; cass 1904; 1 Audiocassette 61 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 629
      - Mass Choir Rehearsal, 1995 August 15; 21-6; cass 1905; 1 Audiocassette 25 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 630
      - Interview with Bertrand Agot, GMWA Participant from Paris, 1995 August 16; 21-7; cass 1906; 1 Audiocassette 30 minutes
        Compact disc(s): CDREF 631
  - 1.4. Gospel and African American Music - Miscellaneous, approximately 1982-1996; 6 Audiocassettes approximately 6 hours
    - Classroom Lecture by Composer T.J. Anderson with Q&A, Indiana University, Bloomington, 1982 October 18; 3-1; cass 1823; 1 Audiocassette 43 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 398
      Lecture for Mellonee Burnim's A390 Class.
    - Debbie May, Gospel Music Industry Lecture, Indiana University, Bloomington, 1993; 16-1; cass 1868; 1 Audiocassette 46 minutes
    - Camilla Williams, Classroom Lecture for Mellonee Burnim's Class, Indiana University, Bloomington; Student Presentation about Duke Ellington, 1984; 3-1; cass 1823; 1 Audiocassette 40 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 399
      Access Restrictions
      Student presentation is restricted and may not be accessed.
    - Interview with Donald Vails, Minister of Music, Ebenezer A.M.E., Ft. Washington, Maryland, 1995 March 13; 20-1--20-2; cass 1898--cass 1899; 2 Audiocassettes 142 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 620--CDREF 622
    - Brother James Burress "Round Trip" (I Timothy 3:16), Detroit Afro-American Mission, undated; 23-1; cass 1909; 1 Audiocassette
      Possibly dubbed from commercial recording.
    - Spirit & Truth / Rejoicensemble, undated; 23-3; cass 1911; 1 Audiocassette
      Possibly a dub of commercial cassette REJK9601 by REJ Music.
- 2. African and Cuban Religious Music, approximately 1990s; 41 Audiocassettes + 8 videocassettes, 2 audiotape reels (2 hours, 9 minutes), 33 slides; (approximately 37 hours)
  - 2.1. African American Church Musical Exchange in Santiago de Cuba, approximately 1990s; 4 Audiocassettes 3 hours, 24 minutes
    - Coro Nacional de Cuba Performance, approximately 1990; 6-1; cass 1828; 1 Audiocassette 40 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 406
      Sung in Spanish; dub of commercial LP.
    - First Baptist Church, Santiago de Cuba, Sala de Dolores, African American Church Musical Exchange, Public Concert, 1990 November 1-4; 6-2--6-4; cass 1829--cass 1831; 3 Audiocassettes 164 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 407--CDREF 409
      Sung in English with commentary primarily in English with Spanish translations; Unclear whether this is a continuous concert or a series of concerts.
  - 2.2. Monrovia, Liberia: Religious Music of Americo-Liberians, 1989 June 10-16; 4 Audiocassettes 4 hours, 4 minutes
    - Tuesday Cottage Prayer Band, Choir Rehearsal, 1989 June 10; 5-2; cass 1825; 1 Audiocassette 27 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 402
    - St. Peter's Lutheran Church. Morning Worship, Children's Day, 1989 June 11; 5-1; cass 1824; 1 Audiocassette 95 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 400--CDREF 401
    - Tuesday Cottage Prayer Band, Noon Worship Service, 1989 June 15; 5-3; cass 1826; 1 Audiocassette 45 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 403
    - Tuesday Cottage Prayer Band, Noon Worship Service, 1989 June 16; 5-4; cass 1827; 1 Audiocassette 77 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 404--CDREF 405
  - 2.3. Malawi, 1983-approximately 1990s; 33 Audiocassettes + 6 videocassettes; (approximately 30 hours)
    English, Chichewa, and other Malawian languages.
    - 4 Young Men from Blantyre Secondary School, 1983 January 23; 4-1; cass 1822; 1 Audiocassette 4 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 397
    - St. Michael and All Angels Choir (Jimmie Kupindu, leader), 1992; 4-1; cass 1822; 1 Audiocassette 9 minutes
    - Chancellor's College, University of Malawi, Zomba. Choral Workshop, Participants' Concert, 1991; 7-1; cass 1832; 1 Audiocassette 95 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 410--CDREF 411
      See also V-6.
    - [Chancellor's College, University of Malawi?], Zomba. Concert and Choral Workshop, 1991 March; 7-2; cass 1833; 1 Audiocassette 79 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 412--CDREF 413
    - Chancellor's College, University of Malawi, Zomba. Choral Workshop, 1991; V-6; VC 552; 1 Videocassette
      See also cass 1832--cass 1833.
    - Masowe Apostolic Church, Zomba, Malawi, 1991 April 20; 7-3--7-4; V-3; cass 1834--cass 1835; VC 549; 2 Audiocassettes + 1 videocassette (VHS); (105 minutes)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 414--CDREF 416
    - Field Interview Conducted by Unidentified Research Assistant with Burnim Asking Questions through Translator, 1991; 7-4; cass 1835; 1 Audiocassette 9 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 416
    - Assemblies of God Church, Zomba, Malawi. Worship Service and Sermon, 1991 April 21; 7-5--7-6; V-4; cass 1836--cass 1837; VC 550; 2 Audiocassettes + 1 videocassette (VHS); (137 minutes)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 417--CDREF 419
    - Chancellor's College, Zomba, Malawi. Feedback Interview with Members of Masowe Apostolic Church, 1991 April 22; 7-7--7-9; cass 1838--cass 1840; 3 Audiocassettes 200 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 420--CDREF 424
    - Harare, Zimbabwe. Ethnomusicology Program, Performance of Indigenous African Music, 1991 April 10; 7-10; cass 1841; 1 Audiocassette 12 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 425
    - Chancellor's College, [University of Malawi?]. Morning Worship, 1991 April 28; 7-11; cass 1842; 1 Audiocassette 48 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 426
    - Masowe Apostolic Church, Blantyre, Malawi. [Worship Service], 1991 April 27; 7-12--7-13; V-5; cass 1843--cass 1844; VC 551; 2 Audiocassettes + 1 videocassette; (148 minutes)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 427--CDREF 429
    - Field Observations on CCAP Ndirande Service, Blantyre, Malawi, 1991 April 7; 7-14; cass 1845; 1 Audiocassette 21 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 430
    - Ndirande CCAP, Blantyre, Malawi. Worship Service, 1991 April 7; 7-15; cass 1846; 1 Audiocassette 94 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 431--CDREF 432
    - Zomba Catholic Cathedral, Zomba, Malawi. Worship Service, 1992 March 22; 8-1; cass 1847; 1 Audiocassette 86 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 433--CDREF 434
    - St. Charles Catholic Church Choir, Zomba Catholic Cathedral, Zomba, 1992 March 23; 8-2; cass 1848; 1 Audiocassette 47 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 435
    - Nhango Salvation Singers, Zomba, Malawi, 1992 March 22; 8-3; cass 1849; 1 Audiocassette 66 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 436
    - "Mbilia Bel" - African Popular Music, approximately 1990s; 9-1; cass 1850; 1 Audiocassette 47 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 438
      Probably a dub of a commercial LP.
    - Choral Workshop, 1992 March; 9-1; V-7; V-8 (copy); cass 1850; VC 553; VC 554 (copy); 1 Audiocassette + 1 videocassette; (42 minutes)
    - Choral Workshop, Participants Concert, 1992 March; 9-2; V-9; cass 1851; VC 555; 1 Audiocassette + 1 videocassette; (54 minutes)
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 439
    - Interview about Choral Workshop with Moses Pondani, Post-Secondary School Teacher and Choir Director, 1992; 9-3; cass 1852; 1 Audiocassette 11 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 573
    - Vaal Reef Choir, Zomba, Malawi, 1992 March 25; 10-1; cass 1853; 1 Audiocassette 67 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 574
    - Interview about Vaal Reef Choir of South Africa with "Albert", 1992; 10-2; cass 1854; 1 Audiocassette 46 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 575
    - Daniel Kachamba Memorial Cassette, undated; 23-2; cass 1910; 1 Audiocassette 62 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 636
    - Dagara Gyil by Bernard Woma, Ghanaian Music, undated; 23-4; cass 1912; 1 Audiocassette
      Commercial item.
    - Timthokoze, Mhango Salvation Singers, Zimra (BMC-001), undated; 23-5; cass 1913; 1 Audiocassette
    - Selections from Choral Workshop, Zomba, Malawi, etc., undated; 23-6; cass 1914; 1 Audiocassette 59 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 637
    - Youth Choir Music, 1989; 23-7; cass 1915; 1 Audiocassette
    - Afrika Singt Nyimbo za ku Malawi, Chormusik aus Malawi, undated; 23-8; cass 1916; 1 Audiocassette
  - 2.4. Miscellaneous, undated; 2 Audiotape Reels (2 hours, 9 minutes); + 2 videocassettes
    - African American Folklore: Interview on Storytelling and Joke Telling, approximately 1997; RA1; OR 41; 1 Audiotape Reel 129 minutes
      Compact disc(s): CDREF 339--CDREF 340
      Interviewees appear to be from Kentucky.
    - Ms. Bob Mazro [?], undated; ?; OR 42; 1 Audiotape Reel
      Blank tape?
    - Panpipe Music and Dance, Ngorombe, Zimbabwe, undated; VC 547; V-1; 1 Videocassette
      Possibly a dub of commercial item.
    - Under African Skies, BBC [TV?] Broadcast about Music of Zimbabwe, undated; VC 548; V-2; 1 Videocassette
      Dub of commercial item.
  - 2.5. Slides, undated; 33 Slides
    - Bishops Choir at First Christian Missionary Baptist Church, Indianapolis, Indiana, approximately 1979; N/A; 8 Slides: color
    - [Grace Apostolic Church, Indianapolis, Indiana?]. Bishop's Choir Anniversary Concert, 1979; N/A; 14 Slides: color
    - Gospel Music Workshop of America (GMWA), undated; N/A; 7 Slides: color
    - Black Performers?, undated; N/A; 4 Slides: black & white
- 3. Smithsonian Institution American Folklife Festival, 1984; 4 Videocassettes 7 hours, 51 minutes
  - Philadelphia Stage, 1984 July 1; VC 543; 1 Videocassette: sound, color; 1/2 in.; (VHS) (121 minutes)
    Gospel Quartet Groups - Two Different Sets of Performances (24 minutes)
    Storyteller (10 minutes)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (10 minutes)
    Blues Musicians (Singer and Harmonica Player) (8 minutes)
    Stepping Routine - Male Group (6 minutes)
    Hip Hop Group (Scatter Boys) (7 minutes)
    Five Male Urban/Hip Hop Dancers (10 minutes)
    Gospel Quartet (8 minutes)
    Female Urban/Hip Hop Dancers (2 minutes)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (15 minutes)
    Steppin' Routine - Male Group (5 minutes)
    Hip Hop Group (Scatter Boys) (12 minutes)
    Five Male Dancers - Urban/Hip Hop Styles (4 minutes)
  - Philadelphia Stage, July 5, 1984; VC 544--VC 545; 2 Videocassettes: sound, color; 1/2 in.; (245 minutes)
    VHS 171
    R&B A Cappella Vocal Group (15 minutes)
    West Philadelphia Version of Breakdancing (13 minutes)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (17 minutes)
    Gospel Group - Four Females (15 minutes)
    Blues Performer, Spoons (3 minutes)
    Blues Performer - Robert "Washboard" Young (7 minutes)
    Hip Hop Featuring Two Female MCs (Rappers) (10 minutes)
    Hip Hop Featuring Two Male MCs (Rappers) (9 minutes)
    Hip Hop: Breakdancers (12 minutes)
    VHS 172
    Behind the Scenes and Audience Shots at Smithsonian Folklife Festival (3.5 minutes – no audio)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (3.5 minutes – no audio)
    Behind the Scene Shots (5.5 sec.)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (2.5 minutes)
    Stepping Routine - Male Group (22 minutes)
    Male Breakdancers (45 sec. – no audio)
    Tap dancers - Male and Female (7.5 minutes)
    Female Dancers/Urban Styles (2 minutes)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (11 minutes)
    Female Teenage Singer-Dancers (2.5 minutes)
    Tap Dancers - Male and Female (28 minutes)
    Spoons Performer (4.5 minutes)
    Steppin' Routine - Male Group (3 minutes)
    Male MCs (Rappers) (3 minutes)